







CSM, Enterprise Business Analyst seeking roles in IT Project
Management, Requirement Gathering, Solution Designing, Identity
Management, Information Security, Data Analysis, SDLC, Process
Improvement, Oracle, SQL, MS-Access, MS Visual source safe, RSA-SecureID



Highest Degree: Masters [Management Information

Current Designation: Enterprise Business Analyst - IT Project Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Management

Current Company: Zycron

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Pune, Chandigarh

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Verified: Phone Number

Key Skills: Enterprise Business Analyst,IT Project Management,Requirement Gathering,Solution Designing,Identity Management,Information Security,Data Analysis,SDLC,Process Improvement,Oracle,SQL,MS-Access,MS Visual

Systems]

source safe,RSA-SecureID,PowerBroker

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Are sponsible, self-starter and versatile professional with extensive Identity and Access management, business, and data analysis experience.

Provided technical solutions to complex problems and supported broad spectrum of internal business and technical clients based worldwide.

Possess strong analytical and communication abilities with experience working in a multicultural banking environment. Worked with global teams with diverse culture.

Experienced in full Software Development Life Cycle, including Requirement Analysis, Design, Development, Quality-assurance, Implementation and Maintenance of applications.

Proven ability to work independently, in a multi-tasking environment and within timelines.

Track record of managing work to achieve milestones on time and within budget in a fast-paced environment.

Excellent communication, analytical, reasoning, interpersonal, and presentation skills.

Work Experience

Zycron as Enterprise Business Analyst - IT Project Management Jun 2017 to Till Date

Worked as Enterprise Business Analyst at Information Services Division - Project Management Office.

Worked with leading teams to drive process improvement and functionality enhancement efforts

Conducted brainstorming workshops to understand Current state and discuss requirements for Future state of processes.

Troubleshooting and resolving access management and provisioning workflow errors.

Performed and monitored Identity and access management activities.

Updated existing access management and provisioning workflows.

Executed and track security process related activities including User ID management.

Managed operations within the IAMenvironment including application upgrades and certificate management. Created new and maintained existing SOD policies in SailPoint.

Worked with leads of different divisions (Treasury and Tax, Police department, Fire department, Traffic, HR, Finance) to understand respective requirements.

Coordinated on implementations of infrastructure components including requirements, testing, and quality assurance. Worked with business teams to get approval and implement recommendations.

Coordinated on implementation of multiple projects such as ServiceNow Portal, Federal funded research project, Oracle-Center of Excellence etc. simultaneously.

Coordinated with QA team and performed testing to ensure the implementations match the requirements.

Analyzed production data and prepared reports and dashboards using Excel/PowerPoint and other MS-Office tools to present concrete information that help in planning projects.

Responsible for the identification, on-boarding and training of Identity management technology tools and processes.

First Tennessee Bank as Business Analyst

Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Jun 2015 to Mar 2017

Coordinated with different application owners to resolve the Access violations.

Managed app-onboarding meetings with application owners.

Effectively participated and resolved SailPoint production issues within IAM and communicated the resolution with end users

Interacted with the business leads to gather requirements for the in-scope applications, including entitlement information, User access & security model, existing IT roles & existing SOD policies required for IIQ configuration.

Coordinated and maintained Sterling way gateway set up for file-based apps in SailPoint.

Coordinated on entitlements data and clean up activity with application owners.

Coordinated and managed role membership certification.

Provided support to end users through the entire process of Access Certification.

Coordinated with Audit teams to fulfil their SOX application's audit requirements.

Coordinated the entire lifecycle of enhancements required in SailPoint for a large business acquisition.

Analyzed current methodologies to enhance the incident response program, including the life cycle of an incident from pre-incident preparation to final incident report.

Identified, responded to and/or escalated issues & risks as per requirement.

Performed in-depth analysis and implemented solutions for various processes, tools and services, products and application/infrastructure operations which have resulted in increased efficiency & client excellence

Coordinated and participated in application testing for virtual security and fulfillment applications during new version/fix releases to ensure successful production rollout.

Analyzed the applications by executing the necessary steps to enrich the quality of the data maintained within the application.

Accountable for the management and execution of daily requests and emails in a high-volume environment. Gathered, documented, and communicated requirements by interacting with technical and non-technical teams and followed up with same for implementation of the projects.

Facilitated research and gap analysis to determine access ownership and target system access details.

Participated in design and project implementations with involvement of numerous IT professionals and business partners

Provided reports and metrics using Excel, Access and Visual Basic.

Collaborated extremely well with Compliance team and other cross-functional partners, including Technical, implementation team and non-IT business partners.

Citi Bank as Information Sec. Analyst

Sep 2013 to Nov 2014

Lead the global projects recommended by Federal Reserve Bank by understanding project management life cycle and handled deliverables independently with little oversight.

Reviewed and analyzed current tools and applications for potential improvements and provided secure solutions, documented them and have them implemented.

Drafted and analyzed corporate security policies and standard documents.

Review and evaluate entitlement policies that allow system administrators, database administrators, and developers super-user access

Utilized and supported inhouse tools as well as worked on SUN-IDM

Provided Information security support to development teams worldwide for Level-1 team escalations utilizing internal tools, emails, phone, and applications for request tracking (ResolveIT) and incident tracking/management (ServiceNow) as per ITIL standards.

Drove and helped with server and account inventory cleanup efforts for UNIX, Solaris. Drove global security efforts delivering closure of multi-year projects specific to owner and resource accountability. Analysed project stakeholders, worked collaboratively with project leads and other partner teams to develop, manage, implement, and maintain transformation plans.

Communicated project plans and updates to project team, stakeholders, and management.

Performed gap analysis on current tool policies against standard requirements to determine necessary modifications. Identified and verified policy owners and performed testing on data integrated into the Employee Entitlement Review System (EERS)

Coordinated with Security team for implementation of automated access management and entitlement system.

Reviewed current remote authentication and worked to make it more secure.

Worked on UNIX (M-editor, K-shell) to create security policies and perform provisioning.

Analysed and documented business requirements by interfacing with different managers and coordinated with development teams to implement them.

Performed functional and UAT testing to assure the system meets requested requirements.

Extracted data from different multi-terabyte business intelligence platforms into excel/csv files, transformed it, analysed, correlate it for various purposes and uploaded processed data as per client's requirements.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Kurukshetra University in 2006

PG: Masters (Management Information Systems) from Wilmington University in 2012

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience	
Windows 10, UNIX (Vi-editor, HP/SUN)		
MAC		
Oracle, SQL, MS-Access		
Microsoft office, MS Visio, SharePoint		
ServiceNow, SailPoint		
Project, MS Visual source safe		
RSA-SecureID, PowerBroker		
HP(QualityCenter)		

1 11 (SCICITY COLICE)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
French				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.